In today's video, I'm going to make this
Haren's chocolate hazelnut ice cream.
It's a chocolate ice cream with a
hazelnut chocolate kind of swirl to it.
It used to be really good, and [music]
now it's absolutely shocking. So, let's
talk about what went wrong with it and
make it as good as we always wanted it
to be.
Yeah, I love this flavor. like a milk
chocolate profile ice cream with to coin
Ben and Jerry's term chocolateaty kind
of swirl that was hazelnut flavored and
it was really nice and for some reason
uh they changed the recipe for their
chocolate hazelnut swirl and it it's
just grainy gritty and pretty nasty now.
And I even got in contact with them and
they fobed me off with crap saying that
they changed the recipe to suit people's
pallets across the world. Excuse my
language. That's just bollocks. That's
just crap that some large corporation
has told you because they're trying to
cut costs and make more money off of the
people that buy it. So, when you look at
the ingredients, let me get my phone.
I'm going to put a screenshot of this
actually up here while I read it. But it
is chocolate hazelnut ice cream.
Ingredients is cream, concentrated
skimmed milk, sugar, chocolate hazelnut
swirl, which is made up from icing
sugar, palm oil, sunflower oil,
hazelnuts, cocoa, milk ingredients,
natural flavoring, sunflower, lethin,
liquid egg yolks, unsweetened chocolate,
cocoa, and natural flavor. So, a couple
of things to to kind of point out in
there and try and let you understand
what they put in there cuz it's really
difficult to tell. Now, concentrated
skin milk. So that is a fancy ass way of
saying they have taken milk solids, so
skim milk powder, dairy proteins, that
kind of thing, and put it into skimmed
milk to increase the solids. That is one
way to do it. And you can also take skim
milk, evaporate off some of that water
to increase the solids in your resulting
liquid. Same thing. Two different ways
of getting to the same result. That's
what that is. Okay. Lauran hazelnut. The
flavor profile this of this is exactly
the same as the Harendars ice cream. So,
we're going to get pretty close to it.
So, what are we going to need for this
Handar chocolate hazelnut ice cream? For
the Haren chocolate hazelnut ice cream
base, you're going to need 700 g of 2%
milk, 327 g of cream, between 33 and 36%
fat, 257 g of sugar, 65 g of skim milk
powder, 35 g of 70% chocolate, 45 g of
cocoa powder, between 20 and 24% fat, 60
g of egg yolks, 5 g of vanilla extract.
And for the actual hazelnut chocolate
swirl, we're going to do this a little
bit better quality than häenarss do cuz
that's the crappiest part of the whole
thing. And for that, you're going to
need 150 g of milk chocolate, 30 g of
cocoa powder, 60 g of milk, 20 g of
refined coconut oil, 10 g of corn syrup
or honey, and 7 g of hazelnut extract.
Let's get everything ready for the ice
cream base and get going. This is making
a 1.5 L batch. If you're making it in a
Ninja Creamy Deluxe, then have it. If
you're making this in a normal Ninja
Creamy, then divide it into three. So,
700 g of milk, 327 g of cream, 257 g of
sugar, 45 g of cocoa powder. I'm using 7
Hills cocoa powder cuz it's a milk
chocolate profile. 35 g of 70%
chocolate. This is actually 75%, but
it's close enough. 65 grams of skimm
milk powder, three egg yolks. So 60
grams, you know, it's not going to make
be the end of the world if you use two
or four. So, you know, somewhere around
there. That's all the ingredients apart
from the vanilla extract. We're going to
put that in once it's cooled down a bit.
So, let's get this on heat. Bring this
up to around 75° centigrade, which is
this in Fahrenheit. We're getting up to
that temperature because we're going to
cook the egg yolks. Get that lethin out
of them and enable the lethin to
actually do something to our recipe. If
you don't cook the egg yolks, then
what's the point of putting them in
because the less than will do nothing.
You'll get a very mild eggy kind of
taste and it won't benefit the ice
cream. If you overcook your egg yolks,
you're going to scramble them. So, 75
centrade. Whilst the base is heating up,
couple of notes. If you want to use a
stabilizer, you absolutely can. Around
1.2 2 1.5 g per kilo in this recipe. You
can heat egg yolks up to 85 C, just keep
stirring them. Any higher than 85, so
you know, if you if you go up to 90,
they're going to start cooking out. So,
just be careful with that temperature.
If you want to use a stabilizer, maybe
go for something with a lower
temperature range. If you can't get a
cocoa powder that is a milk chocolate
profile, then use less of a stronger
dark chocolate profile cocoa powder.
It's absolutely fine. Cocoa powder
generally does doesn't have any sugar
in. So if your cocoa powder has sugar
in, then you're using drinking
chocolate, which is a very different
thing. So please don't do that. So I
heated this up to 82° centigrade for
transparency. I used locust bean gum as
an aside. So stabilizer is optional in
this because we're using the eggs. So
we're using the less thin to bond the
ingredients together. You can get a
better result by adding a small amount
of stabilizer for this. This is 1.5 kilo
batch. So, if you want to add
stabilizer, up to 1.5 g will be enough
because we have that's not eggs, the
eggs in here as well. So, with that all
heated up, let's get this in our
container.
That will go in the refrigerator. And
we're going to add our vanilla extract
just before we churn.
So, we are going to pre-chill our ice
cream machine down. And whilst that's
happening, we're [music] going to
prepare our milk chocolate hazelnut
ganache. So, in this pan, we're going to
start with our good quality milk
chocolate. And we are going to add in
our cocoa powder. I'm using 7 Hills
cocoa powder. It's great. Into that,
we're going to add our coconut oil. This
is refined, so it doesn't taste coconut.
And then followed by our milk. [music]
Any kind of milk you like is fine. This
is going to go on a hob, and we're going
to heat it up. It's going to look really
dry to start with. Don't forget the corn
syrup or honey. And once it's heated up,
we're going to add in our extract and
pour it into a container. Let it cool
down a little bit. I'm going to pop it
in the fridge for about 5 or 10 minutes
until [music] the ice cream is churned.
Now, we're going to take the ice cream
base out and stir it up nicely. But
before we do, in goes our vanilla
extract. It's a really nice vanilla
extract. I've mentioned this before, I'm
sure. Let's get it stirred. Get it in
your machine and get it spinning.
Next, we're going to start loading up
really nice texture as you can see. And
we're going to layer in our ice cream
and our chocolate hazelnut. It's kind of
a ganache fudge. It's delicious. And
just keep layering it up. Give it one
kind of mix, but don't over stir it cuz
you want some big chunks of that ganache
in there. Pop it in the freezer cuz now
it's time to dish up.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Hagen's chocolate hazelnut. Um, I made
two versions of the addin. Actually, I
did the ganache version, which is the
one that I filmed, and I made a slightly
more traditional version just using
chocolate, coconut oil, and the hazelnut
extract. They produced two different
results. One was is like a chewy
chocolate hazelnut, which is this one.
And the other one was a kind of a little
more traditional snap kind of chocolate.
But, um,
the flavor of the ganache one is
perfect. To be fair, the flavor of both
is perfect.
[sighs] Honestly, that ganache is just
heavenly.
That's a massive spoonful of it.
The Hagen's version is kind of somewhere
between the two. It's not just a
chocolate snap and it's not a ganache
version. It's some weird hybrid.
Personally, I prefer that ganache
version. It's just heavenly. The flavor
is absolutely spot on. You got a really
nice milk chocolate ice cream. You can
make this without egg yolks, no problem
at all. Just take them out. Uh use
stabilizer and emulsifier. It really
helps. Emulsifiers really help in
chocolate ice cream because you've got
different types of fat in there. And it
helps to bring those different sources
of fat together with the water to create
a much more uniform base. the ganache.
Yeah, I know it's a little bit more work
than, you know, melting chocolate, put a
bit of coconut oil and and extract in
there, but it's really, really worth it
with this. You get exactly the same
flavor profile as you do from the
hoganache, chocolate hazelnut, but a
much better texture ice cream, and that
hazelnut ganache is brought [music] from
angels down into your bowl. It's
delicious. I've been meaning to make
this for quite a while. It was suggested
what, 18 times in the comments of
various videos. So, here you go. Hagen's
chocolate hazelnut. Thanks very much for
watching. Please remember to like and
subscribe. It really helps this channel
grow. And I will see you next week when
I make some other ice cream that I don't
know currently what that will be.